I trade for about 2 hours a day and can
make anywhere from $3 to $10,000 a
session. But this wasn't the case 9
years ago when I got started and I was
feeling completely lost, completely
confused, wasting time. And it took me
years of trial and error just to figure
out that I didn't need to pull off a
miracle or wait years and years to
master complicated trading concepts just
to be able to scale my trading up to 100
to $250 per day. And what's funny is
that most traders don't know that as
long as you have a repeatable and simple
strategy to follow that's designed to
scale, you can pretty quickly get from
100 to 50 plus per day. But that's only
if you actually know how to do it and
have a process. So that process is
exactly what I'm going to show to you in
this video. So, I'm going to share with
you my full strategy and process that I
followed that you can basically start
with however much or little capital you
want and how exactly to be able to scale
it up to daily goals all designed around
trading for 1 to 2 hours per day. So, if
you're working or you're in school or
you're locked in on trading, ready to go
full force. This is going to be a simple
process to follow to lock in on trading
scale without wasting time and money.
Okay, so like I said, what I'm going to
be showing you is basically modeled
around trading for 1 to two hours per
day. and it's how to start trading to be
able to scale up to this daily goal.
Now, this daily goal isn't set in stone.
I'm going to show you how to basically
apply this to anything that fits with
your schedule or your goals, but I'm
just basing it off of this numbers so
you can understand basically this game
plan. So, first thing that I'm going to
be showing you is how to actually
approach trading the correct way.
There's a lot of mistakes that people
make psychologically and
application-wise. We're going to fix
that. Step two, picking the market that
is actually right for you. There's a
bunch of options depending on your
objectives, where you live, etc. We'll
go over that. Step three, I'm going to
show you my simple, repeatable trading
strategy that I follow. And this is the
strategy that I use to be able to have
the single best week of my entire
trading career. So, I'm going to be
showing you that framework and how to
apply it daily. Then, step four, in
addition to applying it daily, I'm going
to show you exactly how I grow accounts
in a realistic path to follow. This is
what I've been able to do this year with
this trading model, in this framework.
And keep in mind, this is with a 47% win
rate. I'm not right all the time. I'm
probably not the craziest trader on the
internet where they're claiming to make
millions of dollars every single month.
This is me grinding out after 9 years to
be able to grow myself up gradually. And
what I want to remind to you guys is
that comparison is the thief of joy.
Everybody is in their own lane on their
own timeline. I'm just going to be
showing you my timeline, but make sure
you take it one day at a time and focus
on yourself and don't focus on what
other people are doing. Okay? And even
though what I'm doing right now I'm very
proud of, this was definitely not always
the case. In the very beginning of my
trading career, I was having full days
like this. Even though I still have days
like this, by the way, where all you're
doing is losing. That's part of trading.
But this is a very frustrating stage if
you're not looking at trading the right
way. Now, if you are looking at it the
right way, losses are normal, especially
when you're learning. But as long as
you're on the proper path, it's not a
waste of time. But I was literally just
wasting time because I was looking at
trading the wrong way. Okay. So, what
I'm aiming on showing you today is if I
started right now from zero, how would I
start trading and then be able to get to
this daily goal and basically build the
framework to set any daily goal that I
want. Okay? And that's going to start
with step one, which is how to approach
trading the right way. Because this is
how most people do it. And this is why a
lot of people have issues and why a lot
of people will never break into the
profitable stage. And that's because you
start off chasing in trading focused
around profits. Obviously, we're trading
to make money, right? But that doesn't
mean that you need to only play with
that objective. If you want to
accomplish anything in life that's
complex, chasing the end result is
almost always going to lead you to
failure because you're going to be
focusing on the wrong things in the
early stages. And that's why it's
difficult to get to the final
destination is because it's not obvious
what you need to focus on if you're just
staring at the shiny object. You're just
trying to go towards the shiny object.
That's going to lead you astray unless
you have the right fundamentals. That's
why it's important to have mentors who
have done this to be able to show you
how to sort of circumvent all of that.
So, this is how most people do it. They
find a trading strategy approach online
and then they immediately go and try to
open a trading account. Maybe you've
done this. You've opened the trading
account and said, "Okay, I want to try
to at least make, you know, $1,000 this
week." All you're doing is trying to
trade whatever general approach you've
learned with the dollar amount in mind.
What this does to humans is it makes you
change your behaviors, which are
extremely important to have focused when
you're starting off with your trading
journey. The behaviors of what you do
shouldn't be dictated around your
desires to make money. That's the
literal opposite thing that you're
supposed to do, and that's how money is
extracted out of people who are not
profitable in the markets. So, the way
that professional traders actually do
this, and this is the right way to go
about it, is something called proxy
goals. So, obviously, our goal is to get
to our dollar amount. what a proxy goal
is. It's basically a compartmentalized
sort of separated goal that as long as
you focus on these things that don't
directly relate to the end goal. All of
them come together and by default end up
giving you your desired result. So I'll
explain a little bit further. Trading
concepts are important but we need to
have fixed rules. Those rules are going
to allow us to measure our own
performance. So concept comes first.
Then we need actual rules within our
trades. When X, Y, and Z happens, that's
where I'm entering the market. And all
we want to do as traders is find
something called expectancy. This is how
much money we can expect to make each
time we place a trade within these rules
whether we win or lose. And all we're
trying to do is make that a positive
value. So the way we can do this and the
way you should start off trading
whenever you're starting is literally
come up with your strategy have your
rules and then test implementing these
rules over say a month. And what we're
looking for is something called units of
R. Okay. Okay. And what these units of R
are basically allowing us to do is if
say we want to enter the market here.
Say our rules are saying we need to
place an entry here. We'll set a fixed
amount of risk for an anticipated amount
of profit. Say for this example, we have
a 1:3 riskreward ratio. Meaning one unit
of risk or negative 1R is what we're
putting on the table for the opportunity
to make three units of risk back. If
we're risking say 100 on this, we would
be looking to make 300 over here if
we're right about our trade. But we
don't need to worry about the money
right now. All we need to do is treat it
like a game and literally look at it as
negative -1R if we lose and plus 3R or
however many R we make if we're right
about our trade idea. What this is going
to allow us to do as traders is be able
to evaluate our behavior trading this
strategy over a certain amount of trades
and figure out in a very simple number
whether or not we're profitable or not.
What this is going to do is then design
how much we need to risk per trade or
how much money we need to put towards
this in order to then hit our dollar
amount goal for the day, for the week,
for the month. Notice how we haven't
even opened an account yet. That's
because you don't need to do that until
you have all of this stuff figured out.
Okay, so let's run through this R
calculation. Say we have our simple rule
set. We do something called back test
over 30-day period of when we're trying
to trade. And I'm going to show you my
strategy in Onreal chart application
here in a second. But just so that you
understand, say we do 30 total trades
and we net [music] out 15 R. All we need
to do is follow this formula, which may
seem slightly complicated, but it's
really not. And all we're trying to do,
like I said, is figure out what this
unit of risk needs to be in dollar terms
or percent terms of your account. And
that's going to be our R. So if we take
our goal of 250 a day, but like I said,
this can work with any amount. and say
our strategy produces 30 trades a month.
And say that strategy is able to make
overtime positive 15 units of risk over
those 30 trades. That's going to mean
that of the 30 trades that we take, if
our goal is 250, that's giving us a
monthly goal of this amount. So all we
need to do is take the total we're
looking to make based off of our daily
goal and figure out what our trading
strategy followed very repeatably and
very simply can produce us in terms of
R. And then we're dividing that total
amount which is going to show us how
much we need to risk in this risk area
in order to by default hit this daily
goal and hit this amount that we set for
ourselves. Okay, which once again can be
calculated with this calculation and can
be done with $10, $50, $100. I'm going
to show you way more examples of
actually how to figure this out. And
that is going to allow us to pick a
monetary goal based around our strategy.
Then we're going to open an account and
actually start to trade it once we have
proof of concept. What this is going to
do is number one, prevent you from
wasting money and making really
expensive mistakes by opening accounts
too soon. But it's also going to set the
expectation that all you need to focus
on is your trading and being consistent
and not focusing on money and letting it
be a byproduct of you being a good
trader instead of trying to be a good
trader to make money. You see what I'm
saying? That right there is like the
secret sauce of trading. So now we
understand those fundamentals. Let's get
into step number two, which is figuring
out what market to trade and what
instrument to trade. So, there's a few
common ones that traders are going to
choose from. We have stocks, futures,
forex, and crypto. With the stock
market, it's very liquid. There's a lot
of participation. It's very regulated,
and it's pretty easy to understand. The
only downside is that you need a lot of
capital to get started. There's not
really any sort of leverage capability,
and you're limited from market open
hours, which is from 9:30 Eastern to
4:00. So if you're not able to trade
during that period, you really can't
trade the stock market. Futures has way
better access to capital. It's nearly
245, just as session breaks. Some of the
downsides are it's not really good for
long-term holds and there is some risk
with leverage there. So that's sort of
the case. So futures is a really really
good option. That's why a lot of people
trade futures. Forex has a larger market
245 requires a very small amount of
capital to get started. However, it's
very news sensitive and it's very hard
to find an edge in forex. You need to
know a lot about geopolitics and how
different countries doing different
things is going to affect how currencies
move. And it's not very well regulated.
Crypto is 24/7. You can start with a low
amount of capital. You can trade or you
can hold. The only downside is sometimes
there are some restrictions depending on
where you live to get access to capital.
Okay? But I have solutions around that
that I'm going to share with you a
little bit later in this video. So
because of these reasons, I'm going to
be focusing primarily on futures and on
crypto. And I'm going to show you how
this can work for both. Okay? Okay, so
in order for us to figure out what
market is right between futures and
crypto, we need to ask ourselves two
questions. First, how much capital do we
really need to take the trades that
we're looking to take? And then question
two, how much money do we want to make
off of these positions? So, if we look
at this trade scenario here, this was a
trade that I took earlier this week with
the team. I was able to enter in here,
make 6.27R,
so 6.27 times the amount I was risking
to be able to profit a little over
$12,000. Okay. So, to answer question
number one of how much money are we
going to need to place a trade like
this? Say if we're looking to risk $500,
for example, on this trade so that if
we're right, we're making around $3,000.
The way we calculate this as traders is
by finding the entry value where we're
looking to enter right here, subtracting
by the stop-loss value, which is going
to give us this value, and then the
dollar amount or percent of the account
that we're looking to risk. So in this
case once again that $500 would be the
dollar amount that we want to risk.
Okay. So if we have 500 divided by this
amount that's going to be 500 divided by
$18 in this case which is the difference
between these two amounts and that's
going to give us the amount of units
that we need to enter at this price in
order to risk exactly $500 and keep that
very very uniform. The only way we're
going to be able to build this
consistently and for you to be
consistent as a trader is to make sure
that your unit of risk is predetermined
and consistent throughout your strategy.
So, if we look at this across the
several different markets, again, we
have stocks. You're not really able to
get any margin or leverage to be able to
get access to more capital. So, the 2200
units is going to cost us in order to
enter the position, even if we're only
risking the $500, $167,000.
So even if we're able to get 2x leverage
or some margin, it still requires a
tremendous amount of upfront capital to
be able to start the trading journey to
head towards that couple hundred per
day. Okay, if we look at the futures
market, this is completely different.
Okay, so in the futures market, we're
operating something called contracts.
Those contracts have certain dollar
amounts per point that the market moves.
So simply put, in a situation like this,
if we wanted to risk $500 and the stop
distance is 7.25 25 points and it's $2
per point. That would mean that our
stop-loss value, so once again, this
value between here would give us $14.5
of risk per contract, which would mean
we'd need 34 contracts at this price,
which most brokers require $50 worth of
margin per operating contract. So, in
order to place a trade like this,
risking that $500, now we only need
about $1,700 worth of capital. Now, we
probably need a little bit more because
we need to account for if the position
starts to go to draw down. But you can
still see this is a dramatically lower
amount required in an account. If you
want to start, say, at 100, now we can
divide this by five and now you only
need say $300 in an account. And with
crypto, we can take this to an even
further level. Once again, we need 2,200
units, which is going to be a notional
value. So, a theoretical value of this
position of $167,000.
Now, what we can do in crypto is
actually be able to use something called
leverage. And what this leverage is
allowing us to do is effectively divide
the amount of actual capital that we
need by whatever our leverage amount is,
which is given by the exchange that
we're trading on. So, for example, if we
wanted to place this exact trade with
2,200 units with the $500 risk with 3137
as our profit target, the capital
required from that trade would go all
the way from the 167,000 at 100x
leverage. Now, we only need about $1,600
worth of capital to be able to place
that trade. Okay? Now, keep in mind,
we're paying fees off of the total
position size. So, the fees are going to
be increased if you're trying to use and
borrow a bunch of money. But even if
you're trying to risk $50 per trade and
you can use 25x leverage, it gives you a
lot more flexibility to be able to place
these actual trades and not need a
tremendous amount of capital in the
accounts. Hence why once again, I'm
focusing primarily today on the futures
in crypto market. But now we actually
have to understand how to get access to
capital in futures and crypto. So
there's two main ways to get access to
capital. The first is something called a
prop firm. This is where you can
basically get the firm to give you
effectively simulated capital and all
you're trying to do is play within their
trade rules and you're able to use say
for example 50k in an account. You pay
say between 50 and $100 to be able to
have access to it. Use the firm's rules
and you get to start off with 50k. Say
your profit target is 55 and your draw
down is 475. If you hit this draw down
value, the only amount of money that
you're liable to pay is the fee that you
paid to be able to enter the challenge.
And then if you're able to get to that
profit target, as long as you're
following within those rules, if you're
able to pass the evaluation and get into
a funded state, any profit that you
make, now you're able to request payouts
on and you're able to earn that capital
trading with the proper large amounts of
money. The second option is using an
exchange and using leverage. This is
most common in crypto trading. Say for
example, we're using that $50 to $100
with 100x leverage can give you access
to say between 5 and 10K with no rules.
Okay? And the way this works is
basically say we have $1,000 in an
account and say we use all of that on a
trade. If we're using no leverage, the
account would have to drop by $1,000 in
order to reach zero and for you to be
liquidated. If you start to add
leverage, say I add 2x leverage, now I'm
going from zero being my draw down to
500. So now we've cut that directly in
half. Say we're using 4x leverage. Now
that means that the price only needs to
go down $250 for us to reach that same
liquidation level. But obviously if it
moves up even this much, we've now
doubled our account. So let's take this
trade as an example. If we wanted to
enter in here and set our stop-loss
value here, if we want to risk, say,
$100, I can click into my trading view
and click on this long position here,
set this up, double click into this, and
I can set that dollar amount. That's
going to require me to get $833
units. So you can see if I'm entering in
at 6661 and I need 833 units, that's
going to bring my total requirement for
the position up to about $55,000
only to risk $100. If I'm able to now
say apply 10x leverage, you'll see the
value remains the same, but now it's
only going to cost me $5600 to enter the
position. And if I use 100x leverage,
you'll see now the cost of this position
is literally only going to cost me $600
worth of capital. A lot of people think
that when you're using leverage, it's
just more implied risk. Really, what
it's allowing us to do is be able to
take positions like this, risking a
predetermined amount and have access to
the capital to be able to take advantage
of these moves. Okay, so now that we've
covered step one of how to approach the
market, and step two of how to pick the
proper market that works with you, let's
get into step number three. and I'm
going to show you the framework that I
use to trade every single day for about
1 to two hours. First, I'm going to
explain it in a diagram. Then, we're
going to look at a bunch of examples
that happened over the past week so you
can see how it actually looks on a chart
and how I execute in real time. Okay,
step number one, we're going to be
waiting for our session open, whether
it's Asia session, London session, New
York session. I'm trading New York
session that opens at 9:30 a.m. And what
I want to do is wait for something
called a change of character. Now a
change of character is effectively where
I have say a downtrend where I have the
highs getting continually lower and the
lows getting continually lower and then
after a lower low we get a candle that
pushes up and produces a new high. That
is a change of character. And so
basically what I'm doing is looking to
identify the first change of character
that happens in this session. In step
number two, what I want to do is see
that change of character, but I also
want to see something called a fair
value gap. Now, a fair value gap is
basically a pocket of momentum where we
see a series of three candles where the
first candle's high wick in the case of
a bullish fair value gap where the
market's moving up does not overlap with
the low of the third candle's wick and
it leaves a space here with no wick.
That is called a fair value gap. There's
bullish fair value gaps and then the
same thing is true in the opposite
direction for a bearish fair value gap.
Those are what we want to look for. Step
three, what I'm waiting for is a
pullback into what's called my golden
61.8 ratio and the middle point of that
fair value gap. So this is something
called a Fibonacci retracement. And
basically what this is going to show us
is premium and discount zones on a move.
And this 61.8 level is a ratio that
price for whatever reason typically
pulls into before having a continuation
in the opposite direction. So, what I
want to do is be able to take my fib
starting here up to the most recent high
point and have a fair value gap align
between this 50 level and this 61.8
level. Assuming that can happen, and it
happens a lot, this is going to allow me
to filter through fair value gaps and
find the most important ones. But then
what I'm going to do is wait for price
to trade into the 50% midpoint of this
fair value gap. And that's going to be
where I'm looking for my entries. What
I'm looking to do with my position is
basically set up my stop loss outside of
the fair value gap producing candle. So
underneath this low would be my stop
loss. So this is my negative 1R. And I
basically want to target 3 to 4R in the
opposite direction. Now I have ways of
holding trades a lot more, but I just
want to focus on a solid framework to
start off with. And what I'm going to be
doing is waiting for a candle to close
over this most recent swing up before
our entry. What that's going to do is
say we get our candle to close above
this level. That's going to allow me to
then reduce this risk all the way to
break even. So now I have zero risk on
the table and I'm just allowing my trade
to run if it's going in my direction.
The reason for that is because if this
is a new uptrend that we're trading
where we have a low, a high, a low here,
and then a new high, if this is going to
continue to trend up, we really
shouldn't have price producing any sort
of close below this level because that
would indicate once again a change of
character, which is indicating a
potential downtrend. So, we want to be
out of the trade. So, this is a good
place for us to be able to reduce risk
so that if we're wrong about a trade,
we're out. And if we're right, we've
eliminated risk and allowed ourselves
play up to our 1:3 1-4 target. So now
let's take a look at how this actually
looks set up on a real chart. Okay, so
right here we have our 930 open. That is
where the session is starting. And
you'll see price was trending up and
then finally produced a new low out of
that uptrend which is now starting a
potential downtrend. So we have our
change of character level. Notice we
have several fair value gaps forming on
this move. And by the way, if you want
to add these to your chart
automatically, you can go in the
description and check out tools, okay?
And you'll see something called a
foundation indicator. This is going to
allow you to be able to add this session
marker here, as well as be able to turn
these fair value gaps on your chart
automatically. But you'll see we have
our change of character and we have our
fair value gap. What I'm going to do is
take that Fibonacci. So, click on this
button on trading view here. Go to my
Fibonacci. Click at the beginning of
this move down to the bottom once we
start to get a push up. And you'll see
this gap is sitting directly at that
61.8 level. Okay, price moved down a
little bit so I have to adjust it. So
this one or this one are going to fit
within our position. So I'm looking for
the midpoint of that area. And I want to
place my stop loss outside of that
potential area. Set my profit box to a 1
to4. And you'll see as price breaks back
up through this level, that area was
immediately responded off of because of
that fair value gap. But now we're
sitting at a good discounted zone.
Immediately starts to reject down. In
this case, we could have reduced risk
underneath that low, but ends up coming
to take us out for a full 1 to4. Now, I
do have strategies to trail this a lot
more, and I'll sort of explain that here
in a second. Okay, so let's go to
another example now. Okay, once again,
we have our 930 open. This level here
gives us our change of character. If we
take our Fibonacci level from there to
here, you'll see we're sitting right at
that 61.8 level. So, we can put our stop
loss like this and say we wanted to risk
$100, that would mean that we need 588
units. So, we can enter in with 588
units. Set our takerit down to 1 to4.
Stop loss up over this high. Okay. And
you'll see price comes right up, rejects
down, makes a close underneath this
[music] swing point. That's where we
bring our stop-loss to break even. So,
now it's a risk-free trade. And now
price comes up and tags us out. A lot of
times these trades are not going to work
out, okay? But that's why we reduce
risk. Okay? So, let's take a look at
another example. We have our 930 open.
Price is still in a downtrend. Notice
how we still didn't get a close or a
change of character over this high yet
until this point where we have a candle
close up over this high level. So once
again, we have a change of character.
Now we can set up our 61.8 which brings
us right into this gap. I can set my
entry right at the midpoint of that gap.
Place my stop loss underneath that
candle up to 1:4. Set my stop loss down
to this level. Take profit up here.
You'll see price trades right into
middle of that area. Now we can reduce
risk to this break even level and allow
the trade to go full profit. And you can
see as an example of one of my trades
from earlier in the month, this is
exactly what I did. Entry was a little
bit late but in that 61.8 area. I reduce
my stop loss into the money as the trade
is moving in my direction. Okay? And I
was able to hold this position a lot
longer. Okay? This is stuff that I talk
about on the private side of my team.
But you can see the opportunity here
just by being able to find these moves
right out of the open and capitalize on
them. Then I locked in profit there.
You'll see just off of one of these
trades out of the open, sometimes I'll
be able to find three to five of these
per session. Just by getting one trade
correct, I'm able to make four times
what I'm risking, which now means I can
proceed to lose four trades in a row
right after that and still be close to
break even on my account. Which brings
us to step number four, which is how to
actually apply this daily to start
growing your account. So, the first
process of this is to obviously take
whatever trading model that you're
using, whether it's this one or another
one, and actually go onto your trading
view, click on this replay feature here,
and just play back a bunch of sessions
and trade it within your rules. And
that's going to give you how much R you
can expect to make based off of
following the strategy over a month. And
all we're trying to do is be able to
figure out whether we're on the green
side of this profitability table or not.
So, for the trades that we're taking, if
we're getting 1 to four, if we're right
20% of the time, we're break even. If
we're right 30% of the time, we're
profitable. If we're right 40% of the
time, we're highly profitable if we're
averaging that one to four. Okay? And I
just had the single biggest week of my
entire trading career last week. So,
this is not necessarily normal for me.
However, this is an example of what I'm
doing. So, I was able to take basically
six trades. Over those six trades, I was
able to make this amount of R over a
week. So that's 14R based off of my 2K
risk. So even with just allowing this
model to play out over a week with that
$250 per trade risk, that's this amount
per week. Okay, even this 14R with $100
per risk would have been a $1,400 week.
And that's why we have students who are
focusing on doing exactly that. You can
take Nednar, one of our students right
now, who's absolutely killing it. And
you can see he's focusing on his units
of risk, proper risk management, but you
can see he's well on his way to being
able to leverage these skills. Okay, you
can see another one from Ned Narb here.
Okay, this is one of our prop firm
traders who trades futures also being
able to absolutely smoke it using the
prop firm approach, but focusing on
these same exact concepts. So, this
right here is exactly what you need to
use to be able to set your goal, test
your information for yourself, and be
able to hit those daily goals or your
trading goals in general. Okay, like I
said, all the tools are in the
description, so you can check that out.
Okay, make sure you hit the like button,
subscribe to the channel if you want to
know when I put other videos out. If you
want to join our private team, I'll link
it right here. Okay, if you want to
trade alongside the team and become a
student, you can check the link out
right here. But until next time, guys, I
will see you all in the next video.